SAMMY SAMKOUGH

862-239-0100 | sammysamkough@gmail.com | Wayne, NJ 07470; New York City, NY 10001 https://sammy.pizza | https://github.com/ssamkough | https://linkedin.com/in/ssamkough

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FULL STACK; MERGE API

SUMMARY:

Software Engineer with 5+ years of industry experience working at startups and SaaS, building in fast paced environments while focusing on customer success. Programming in Python, Django, JavaScript / TypeScript, React, and Postgres.

Areas of Expertise: FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT // WEB DEVELOPMENT // FRONTEND TESTING

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

- Languages HTML; CSS; JavaScript; TypeScript; Python; C#; Java; SQL
- <u>Frameworks</u> React.js; Next.js; Remix; Astro.js; Gatsby.js; Vue.js; Svelte; Django; Node.js; Express.js; React Native
- Applications Git; Postgres; Firebase; GraphQL; Storybook; AWS; Google Cloud; Vercel; Netlify; Chromatic

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Bonny Systems, New York City, NY; Wayne, NJ

Oct 2023 - Present

Founding Engineer

- Achieving over 80% reduction in website load times by improving core web vitals which includes minimizing JavaScript usage, image optimization, and adherence to web standards.
- Partnering with design agencies to build and deploy modern websites and APIs with CI/CD pipelines using content management systems (CMS) like WordPress or advanced front-end frameworks such as Next.js and Astro.js.

Canal, San Francisco, CA; New York City, NY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

Software Engineer

- Developed the onboarding process to adapt to evolving user needs, making product decisions on the fly, utilizing React, Next.js, TypeScript, XState, Django and GraphQL which lead to an overall 40% increase in user satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a fast-moving design / product team of five to create in-house design system that replaced the Shopify Polaris design system which led to an increase of development speed by over 60%.
- Enhanced web application usability across all departments by 60% through leading targeted accessibility training and guidelines for the development team.
- Led the standardization of UI / UX component testing within the in-house design system, significantly reducing component-specific bugs by over 70% using Chromatic and Storybook.

Popstar, Remote USA

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Launched and roadmapped feature-rich iOS application using Swift and Firebase / NoSQL, which offered an elegant vertical video experience, including social interactions such as sharing and commenting on videos.
- Integrated backend Firebase push notifications and cloud messaging enhancing user engagement by 80%.

Decusoft, Hybrid (Ramsey, NJ; Remote USA)

May 2019 - Oct 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Implemented table features like filtering and sorting algorithms using JavaScript, C# / ASP.NET and SQL databases.
- Optimized complex SQL queries which increased the load time performance of the main MySQL table by 50%.

EDUCATION:

Montclair State University, Montclair, NJ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 2019